Gregory Paul Albarian

gregoryalbarian@gmail.com | +1 (818) 588-0106 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Burbank, California

Summary

I am continuously learning on my own, and throughout my 3+ year career, I have produced results by creating analytical conclusions, developing machine learning models, and cleaning data. I also have experience processing data for 3D modelling pipelines, which helps in machine learning pipelines.

Professional Experience

Junior Python Developer | SDLC Technologies | Remote | Apr. 2024 – Dec. 2024

- Optimized over 100 REST API calls to clean and gather data for structuring LLM responses
- Analyzed over 100 coding explanations and programs written in Python, SQL, Java, and C++ generated by Fortune Tech 10 company's LLM
- Enhanced the LLM's accuracy by a 15% increase from data curated throughout my team

Support Engineer (as a Python Developer) | Qualcomm Inc. | San Diego, CA | May 2022 – Dec. 2023

- Simulated the cameras of the Meta Quest Pro and other head-mounted displays (HMD) by rendering 3D meshes of humans in Blender and OpenCV prototype the hardware. Processed data from a CSV file using Pandas and calculated the 3D geometry in NumPy to find placements for the cameras.
- The data pipeline created to automate the 3D renders saved 40% of the time that it would take to process the training data by manually placing the cameras, lights, and meshes.
- Streamlined eye gaze data entry by an internal labelling tool to increase productivity by 60%
- Automated the download of over 20,000 images by integrating a RESTful API into Python code, increasing the training data to improve the performance of machine learning models
- Facilitated communications with third-party data vendors by organizing over 50 meetings, increasing data quality for labels on Azure Data Factory, and transferring it to an on-premises server

Research Assistant | Chapman University | Orange, CA | Sept. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Designed an Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) pipeline with NumPy and Pandas in Python
- Automated a manual workflow using R using time series clustering to analyze patients' stress, depression, and anxiety find 2 major trends in the data on the effects of therapy.

Certifications

Generative AI with Large Language Models | DeepLearning.AI and AWS | Issued Sept.2024 Deep Learning Specialization | DeepLearning.AI | Issued Dec. 2023

Education

Master of Science (M.S.) in Computational and Data Sciences emphasis in applied mathematics and analysis | (3.419/4.0) | Feb. 2021 – Dec. 2021 | Chapman University (Orange, CA)

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science | Mathematics Minor | (3.282/4.0) |

Aug. 2017 – Dec. 2020 | Chapman University (Orange, CA)

Projects

Analyzing Medical Practitioner Stress

 Developed decision trees, SVMs, and neural networks to find what makes medical workers stressed

Dow Jones Dividend Analysis

- Worked to discover a correlation if stocks with higher dividends were traded more by investors
- Coded a script in R finding no correlation between dividends and volumes for the Dow Jones

Markov Music

• A Python scripted Markov Chain model to learn patterns in song lyrics to generate songs.

Skills

Programming languages Python, Java, SQL, Scala, R, C, C++, MATLAB, C#, HTML, CSS, BASH Development tools and Big Data management MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, Git, GitHub, Docker, Unix, Linux, Jenkins (for CI/CD), Amazon Web Servies (AWS) Libraries TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, NLTK, pyspark, OpenCV, Pandas, NumPy, matplotlib, ggplot2, JSON, CSV